[Music]
suppose that a b c and d are all real
numbers then we can build a right
triangle whose leg lengths are given by
the absolute value of B times the
absolute value of c and the absolute
value of a times the absolute value of C
if we assume that c is non-zero then we
can scale this triangle by the value
absolute value of D over the absolute
value of C producing this triangle which
has leg lengths absolute value of B
times absolute value of D and absolute
value of a times absolute value of D
because this new triangle is a scaled
and rotated copy of the original right
triangle when the two triangles are
placed side by side like this they
produce a right angle so that this
picture triangle is a right triangle as
well we can use the Pythagorean theorem
on the original two right triangles to
see that the leg lengths of this new
right triangle are the absolute value of
D times the square root of a squared
plus b squared and the absolute value of
c times the square root of a squared
plus b squared because this new triangle
is also right angled we can use the
Pythagorean theorem to find the length
of the high hotness to be the square
root of a squared plus b squared times
the square root of c squared plus D
Squared but now we know that the
absolute value of AC plus b d is less
than or equal to the absolute value of a
times C plus the absolute value of B
times D from the triangle inequality on
the other hand from this trapezoidal
shape we see that the base length which
is the absolute value of a times C plus
the absolute value of B times D must be
less than or equal to the length of the
hypotenuse of that top triangle which is
the square root of a squared plus b
squared times the square root of c
squared plus D Squared therefore the
absolute value of AC plus b d is less
than or equal to the square root of a
squared plus b squared times the square
root of c squared plus D Squared where a
b c and d are real numbers this is often
referred to as the two variable Koshi
bonyakowski Schwartz inequality
foreign